David Duron Lakeland, Florida 33805 863-274-3419

emt2dev@protonmail.com

https://github.com/curved-arrow

Objective

As a former Emergency Medical Technician, I am transitioning into the information technology and cybersecurity industry where I hope to use my previous experiences and newfound skills to serve my community. I have a passion for critical thinking and the work ethics to work hard until a problem is solved. I am currently in college (online) for software engineering and love working with technology.

Work Experience (Software Development and Information Technology)

Curved Arrow Networks - Software Engineer (08/2021 - Current)

- Remote position that requires a quiet and secure workspace
- Use ETL processes to meet standards for import and export of XML
- Use SQL queries to Create, Test, Debug databases for public safety use
- Create, Deploy, Test, Debug full-stack web applications (LAMP (custom OOP PHP), React, XML, HTML, CSS, Javascript (custom and bootstrap).
- Read existing and Write technical documentation to ensure NEMSIS, NENA standards are met
- Used cloud architecture (directnic.com)
- Ensured full functionality and implementation with public safety agencies.
- Conduct presentations on the application and code.

Kelly Connect - iOS Software Support Desk Remote (03/2020-0/2020)

- Remote position that requires a quiet and secure workspace
- Provide end-user software and hardware support via chat and email for iOS software and apple hardware.
- Use internal APIs to view hardware functionality.
- Use internal APIs to view software functionality.
- Use internal policies to determine network status.
- Use internal policies to schedule repair appointments and shipments.
- Handle protected identifying information per GDPR and information security policies.
- Communicate with supervisory team in a professional manner.
- Clean, store, and secure issued equipment: headset, iMac, ethernet cable, keyboard, mouse.

Tropical Business Consulting - End-User Help Desk Remote (02/2016-04/2019)

- Provide end-user tech support for an Internet Service Provider via phone.
- Use internal APIs to view hardware functionality.
- Use internal policies to determine network status.
- Use internal policies to schedule field technician appointments.
- Handle protected identifying information per GDPR, HIPAA law, and information security policies.
- Communicate with supervisory team in a professional manner.

Work Experience (Other Industries)

Broad Path Healthcare Solutions - Healthcare CSR Remote (11/2021 -02/2022)

- Remote position that requires a quiet and secure workspace
- Handle protected identifying information and protected health information per GDPR, HIPAA law, and information security policies.
- Review and discuss benefits with members regarding pharmacy and other benefits; Discussed and confirmed Medicaid/Medicare enrollment and benefit plan options
- Scheduled member navigator appointment for community resources
- Utilized CMS, Genesys, Outlook, and other systems daily
- Write technical documentation
- Protects/observes patient confidentiality per HIPAA, policies, and procedures.

Tropical Business Consulting - Healthcare CSR Remote (02/2019-04/2020)

- Remote position that requires a quiet and secure workspace
- Scheduled transport for doctor appointments on occasion
- Review and discuss benefits with members regarding pharmacy and other benefits; Discussed and confirmed Medicaid/Medicare enrollment and benefit plan options
- Scheduled member navigator appointment for community resources
- Utilized CMS, Genesys, Outlook, and other systems daily
- Write technical documentation
- Protects/observes patient confidentiality per HIPAA, policies, and procedures.

Federal Contractor - Firefighter/EMT (09/2009-04/2019)

- Provide public information on fire prevention, CPR, and career opportunities.
- Become familiar with city layout, established response routes, policies, and procedures.
- Respond to emergency medical incidents and administer emergency medical treatment.
- Perform search and rescue of individuals in hazardous environments.
- Protects/observes patient confidentiality per HIPAA, policies, and procedures.
- Work with electronic medical and electronic health records

Awards

Presidential Volunteer Service Award

- Awarded by Barack Obama, 2011
- Achieved through the National Volunteer Fire Council
- Gold Level

Education

Hillsborough Community College

- August 2021 to May 2023
- Computer Programming & Analysis Associate's Degree
- Consecutive Dean's List each semester
- Multiple projects in C, Java, C#
- Self-taught: LAMP (including PHP), C++, Javascript, Node.js, React, HTML, CSS, XML

Bossier Parish Community College

- January 2011 to May 2011
- Emergency Medical Technician Certification

Certifications

- Emergency Medical Technician, State of Virginia expires 09/2024
- National Incident Management System 100, 200, 300

Professional References

1. John Carvalho

- former supervisor MB Solutions, LLC and Owner of the company
- www.MBSVB.com
- 195 S. Rosemont Road
- Virginia Beach, VA 23452
- JCarvalho@MBSolu.com
- Office (757) 821-2080
- Fax (757) 821-0244
- Cell/Text (757) 572-7781

2. Brian Walker

- Former Coworker at Reliance Medical Transport
- Former Coworker at MB Solutions, LLC
- 757 254-5358

3. Alina Turbessi-Sok

- 757 814-3288
- Former Corworker at MB Solutions, LLC

EMT Employment History

1. **MB Solutions, LLC** Virginia Beach

- 757 821-2080
- 04/2017 to 06/2017
- left to move to Florida

2. Reliance Medical Transport, LLC 10/2017 to 01/2018

- Federal Contractor
- 757 456-5147
- Virginia Beach
- I told a coworker to stop telling my boss lies about my performance and was fired for "blackmail". A female coworker said that I sexually harassed her and I was suspended pending internal investigation. The company "found" that I was wrongly suspended and I was able to return to work with full pay. I then told that coworker to stop spreading lies or I would contact her college and inform them that she was cheating on her EMT exams (where I unknowingly provided answers). A few months prior, i submitted where i reported a coworker drunk driving a work vehicle.
- Neither employee was disciplined, the female coworker in question is now in the position that I was to be promoted to and the drunk driver spent four years at that company before leaving.
- I was promised a supervisor position prior to these events.

3. Nucare Carolina Ambulance 08/2015 to 09/2016

- Federal Contractor
- Hampton, VA
- 800 380-1947
- Lead project that will allow the VA hospital medical transport system to reduce wait times for appointment scheduling in an effort to reduce veteran suicides while waiting for care.
- Left due to out of court settlement, unable to describe in detail due to agreement, I received funds from this company after the settlement.

4. **Balentine Ambulance, INC** 12/2013 to 03/2014

- Federal Contractor
- Shreveport, LA
- 318-222-5358
- The Operations Director intentionally deposited my paycheck into my account twice, causing my bank account to get closed and I was blamed for attempting to steal from him. This was confirmed by my attorney who spoke with the accounting firm's attorney.
- Left due to accepting full-time position with Safe Bites Traning, not eligible for re-hire.

5. **First Med EMS, INC** 09/2012 to 12/2013

- Federal Contractor
- Company shut down, the largest layoff to affect the EMS community.